vagabondjourney.com 2014-11-22

# Privacy – Vagabond Journey Travel Stories and World Culture

Here at [VagabondJourney.com](http://www.vagabondjourney.com/) I recognize that privacy of your personal information, and education on visitor privacy, is important. The following outlines what types of personal information I receive and collect when you use and visit this site, and how I safeguard your information. Note: I never sell your personal information to third parties.

## Log Files

As with most other websites, [VagabondJourney.com](http://www.vagabondjourney.com/) collects and uses the data contained in log files. The information in the log files include your IP (internet protocol) address, your ISP (internet service provider), the browser you used to visit the site, the time you visited and which pages you visited throughout the site.

## Cookies and Web Beacons

I use visitor cookies to store information. I also use third party advertisements on [VagabondJourney.com](http://www.vagabondjourney.com/) to support the site. Some of these advertisers may use technology such as cookies and web beacons when they advertise on this site, which will also send these advertisers (such as Google through the Google AdSense program) information including your IP address, your ISP , the browser you used to visit the site, and in some cases, whether you have Flash installed. Geo targeting is sometimes used for the purposes of matching advertisements with visitors based on certain attributes that visitor has.

## DoubleClick DART cookies

I also may use DART cookies for ad serving through Google’s DoubleClick, which places a cookie on your computer when you are browsing the web and visit a site using DoubleClick advertising (including some Google AdSense advertisements). This cookie is used to serve ads specific to you and your interests (”interest based targeting”). The ads served will be targeted based on your previous browsing history. DART uses “non-personally identifiable information”. It does not track personal information about you, such as your name, email address, or physical address. You can opt-out of this ad serving on all sites using this advertising by visiting [doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx](http://www.doubleclick.com/privacy/dart_adserving.aspx%20rel=)

You may choose to disable or selectively turn off this site’s cookies or third-party cookies in your browser settings, or by installing programs designed to do as much. However, this can affect how you are able to interact with this site as well as other websites.

Deleting cookies does not mean you are permanently opted out of any advertising program. Unless you have settings that disallow cookies, the next time you visit a site running the advertisements a new cookie will be added.

If there are any questions, please feel free to [contact me](http://www.vagabondjourney.com/contact/).

Walk Slow,

Wade Shepard<
